Guide to the Liza Loop Papers, 1972 - 1984
Department of Special Collections
Loop, Liza. Papers,
1972 - 1984
M1141
Loop, Liza.
6 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Liza Loop, 1986.
Biography
California educator whose interests include computers and education, public-access computing, and software.
Scope and Content
Papers concerning Atari, People's Computer Company, ComputerTown, Homebrew Computer Club, Northwest Computer Club, etc., together with correspondence and the draft of the first VISICALC manual.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Loop, Liza.; Atari.; ComputerTown.; Homebrew Computer Club.; Northwest Computer Club.; People's Computer Company.; Computers.; Computer-assisted instruction.
Collection Contents
- Early volumes1975 - 1981 (Box 1)
  Contains newsletters, including Homebrew, Northwest Computer Club, Hewlett Packard Computer Users Group, TRS Users
- Personal Software, Inc. archiveca. 1979 (Box 1)
  Includes Visicalc developers manual for Visicalc; also includes sales material
- Sonoma County Computer Club [1 of 2]1978 - 1980 (Box 1)
  Includes newsletters of the club. Also includes Strobe Ware User's guide, 1982, and Wagner lecture, 1978
- Sonoma County Computer Club [2 of 2]1978 - 1980 (Box 2)
- Portfolio, Bay Area Atari User's Group1980 - 1981 (Box 2)
  Includes newsletters, receipts, flyers
- Organizations1979 - 1980 (Box 2)
  Includes newsletters
- Math and Sciences Ed[ucation] for Women1978 (Box 2)
- Computer Town / Call computer,n.d., 1 binder (Box 2)
- Newsletters: Kiloboard, CRIS1976 - 1981 (Box 2)
- People's Computers magazine1977 - 1981 (Box 2)
- Atari Home Users guide (Box 2)
- Logo Primer1973 (Box 2)
- Carl Helmers Personal Computer Letters1981, 3 items (Box 2)
- Women and Microcomputingca. 1981, 1 folder (Box 2)
- Computertown: "pre 4/1 draft, has Ramon's comments"ca. 1981, 1 folder (Box 3)
- Technical Education Research Centers1981 - 1983, 1 folder (Box 3)
- Hands-on newsletter (Box 3)
- People's Computer Co. bulletins1972 - 1976, 1 folder (Box 3)
- Solo Works: newsletter1976, 1 folder (Box 3)
- Computers at Lawrence Hall1978, 1 folder (Box 3)
- Computer-using Educators newsletters1979 - 1981, 1 folder (Box 3)
- Computer notes / Boces Center,1980 - 1981, 1 folder (Box 3)
- Computer Professionals for Social Responsibility1982 - 1984, 1 folder (Box 3)
- Atari Corporation materials [1 of 2]1979 - 1981, Includes 2 computer diskettes (Box 4)
  includes documentation, project files, memoranda, Atari 400 (Candy), Atari 800 (Colleen), VCS (Stella). Also contains magnetic diskettes.
- Atari Corporation materials [2 of 2]1979 - 1981, Includes 2 computer diskettes (Box 5)
- Peoples Computing Co.1979 - 1981 (Box 6)
  Contains early issues of this title.
- Infoworld1980 - 1981 (Box 6)
- Byte1976 (Box 6)
- SCCS Interface1976 (Box 6)
- Popular Electronics (Altair Issue): "start of microcomputer revolution"1975 (Box 7)
- Intel (Box 7)
- Varian (Box 7)
- Digital (Box 7)
- Lo*op Center (Computer Educational R & D) (Box 8)
  Contains class material, correspondence, brochures. Also contains People's Computer Company news, 1975.
- SigPC Notes / Special Interest Group on Personal Computing1978 - 1981 (Box 9)
- APL Quote Quad1980 (Box 9)
- People's Computer Comany news, n.d. (Box 9)
- Personal Computing Digest1981 (Box 10)
- The best of Computer Faires, Vol. IV (1979), VI (1981), VIII (1983)1979 - 1983 (Box 10)
- Star Trek Game printoutn.d.
- Pilot Paper tapesn.d.
- Game cardsn.d.
- What do you do after you hit return*, or P.C.C.'s first book of computer games, 1975
- Intel Packetn.d., Includes microchips